# SIRIWAT KASAMWATTANAROTE

# RESEARCH ENGINEER ON BLOCKCHAIN, AI, AND IOT AI TEAM, BLUE WALL JAPAN

SPLINE BUILDING 6F, 1-19-2 DOGENZAKA, SHIBUYA-KU, TOKYO, 150-0043

MOBILE: (+81)080-4925-4569 E-MAIL: SIRIWAT@LIVE.JP, SIRIWAT@BLUEWALL.JPN.COM

WEBSITE: STYLIXBOOM.GITHUB.IO GITHUB: GITHUB.COM/STYLIXBOOM

#### **SUMMARY**

I'm a Ph.D. in Informatics and I pursued my research on real time large scale **visual retrieval** based on information retrieval and data mining. And I did a very big jump for the recent image search technology by applying a data mining technique to the retrieved result. The achievement on the landmark dataset, e.g. Oxford and Paris 5k, 105k, 1M, are about **15% accuracy improvement** beyond the state-of-the-art technology.

Currently, I work as a domain expert, researcher, and architect on Blockchain, AI, and IoT at **Blue Wall Japan** and **lead the frontend dev-team** for one of their project.

Prior to this, I worked as a Blockchain research engineer at **SBI BITS** and did many researches on integrating a blockchain framework (Hyperledger) to Docker, especially Docker swarm. And also I'm now involve in joining these communities together.

#### Technical:

**During my Ph.D.**, I provide several back-end (C++, PHP, and MPI) server services with my own implemented inverted index database and a large-scale HDF5 based file to serve a front-end image search interface based **HTML5** and **JavaScript** [LINK]. This system is running on multiple HPC based Linux servers with my custom build LFS (Linux from scratch) environment.

**During SBI BITS,** for a blockchain based KYC project, **Golang** play the major role in implementing of a chaincode on a **Hyperledger** framework, **Node.js** and **MongoDB** are used in bridging the gap between two communities; the **Hyperledger** and the **Docker swarm.** 

#### **EDUCATIONS**

#### 2016 - Ph.D. in Informatics

- 総合研究大学院大学、日本、
   SOKENDAI [The Graduate University for Advanced Studies], Japan
- Research: Large-scale image and video retrieval, information retrieval, and data mining.
- Thesis: "Query Expansion for Visual Search Using Data Mining Approach"

#### 2012 - M.Sc. in Computer Science

- Chulalongkorn University, Thailand
- Major: CSIT (Computer Science and Information Technology), English program
- Thesis: "Automated video surveillance summarization system"
- GPA: 3.63/4.00

#### 2009 - B.Sc. in Computer Science

- Mahidol University, Thailand
- Major: ICT (Information and Communication Technology), English program
- Senior project: "Intelligent Image Resizing"
- GPA: 3.10/4.00

# INVITED SPEAKER

# Trading Derivatives on Hyperledger [Slide] - LCCC Japan 2016

Siriwat Kasamwattanarote, Fernando Vazquez LinuxCon + ContainerCon, Tokyo, Japan, Jul. 15, 2016

#### Best Student Poster and Demo Award - WMPA 2014

Tell me about TV commercials of this product, <u>Siriwat Kasamwattanarote</u>,
 The 1st Winter School on Multimedia Processing and Applications, Dublin, Ireland, Jan. 6-8, 2014

# **PUBLICATIONS**

# 1. Query Bootstrapping: A Visual Mining based Query Expansion

<u>Siriwat Kasamwattanarote</u>, Yusuke Uchida, and Shin'ichi Satoh, IEICE Transactions on Information and Systems, Vol. E99-D NO. 2, pp 454-466, Feb. 1, 2016.

# 2. PVSS: Portable Visual Search Service for Researchers

<u>Siriwat Kasamwattanarote</u> and Shin'ichi Satoh, The 7<sup>th</sup> International Conference on Internet Multimedia Computing and Service (ICIMCS 2015), Zhangjiajie, Hunan, China, pp. 64:1--64:5, Aug. 19-21, 2015.

# 3. Tell me about TV commercials of this product

Cai-Zhi Zhu, <u>Siriwat Kasamwattanarote</u>, Xiaomeng Wu, and Shin'ichi Satoh, The 20<sup>th</sup> Anniversary International Conference on MultiMedia Modeling, Dublin, Ireland, pp. 242-253, Jan. 6-10, 2014.

#### 4. Connect Commercial Films with Realities

Cai-Zhi Zhu, <u>Siriwat Kasamwattanarote</u>, Xiaomeng Wu, and Shin'ichi Satoh, 2013 International Conference on Multimedia Retrieval, Dallas, Texas, USA, pp. 323-324, Apr. 16-20, 2013.

#### 5. Automated real-time video surveillance summarization framework

Nagul Cooharojananone, <u>Siriwat Kasamwattanarote</u>, Shin'ichi Satoh, and Rajalida Lipikorn, Journal of Real-Time Image Processing, Accepted on 16 Sep. 2012. Springer

# 6. Real Time Trajectory Search in Video Summarization using Direct Distance Transform

Nagul Cooharojananone, <u>Siriwat Kasamwattanarote</u>, Shin'ichi Satoh, and Rajalida Lipikorn, 10<sup>th</sup> International Conference on Signal Processing, Beijing, China, vol. 6297/2010, pp. 932-935, Oct. 24-28, 2010.

7. Real Time Tunnel Based Video Summarization using Direct Shift Collision Detection Siriwat Kasamwattanarote, Nagul Cooharojananone, Shin'ichi Satoh, and Rajalida Lipikorn, 11th Pacific Rim Conference on Multimedia, Shanghai, China, pp. 136-147, Sep. 21-24, 2010.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCES**

# Jan 2017 to Present - Research engineer on Blockchain, AI, and IoT

- at Blue Wall Japan, Inc., Shibuya, Japan
- Leading the frontend development team for one of the project.
- Researching on blockchain technology, AI, image/information retrieval, and related stuffs.

# May 2016 to Dec 2016 – Blockchain research engineer

- at Strategic software development (SSD), SBI BITS, Roppongi, Japan
- Researching a blockchain based framework for a fully distributed trading platform.
- Projects:
  - Blockchain based binary option and smart contract.

- Integration of Hyperledger with Docker swarm.
- Researching and designing the architecture of a blockchain based AML/KYC solution.

#### Oct 2012 to Mar 2016 - Research Assistant

- at Digital Content and Media sciences Research Division,
   国立情報学研究所、National Institute of Informatics [NII], Tokyo, Japan
- Projects:
  - Instance search framework for large-scale image and video retrieval
    - -- Tasks -- Building a full image retrieval system, e.g. several server side services for handling image queries and a client side HTML5-based UI.
  - NII Commercial film retrieval [Demo: <a href="http://www2.satoh-lab.nii.ac.jp/~stylix/cf">http://www2.satoh-lab.nii.ac.jp/~stylix/cf</a>]
    - -- Tasks -- Building a client side UI and several server side retrieval modules.
  - NII KAORI, face retrieval system [Demo: <a href="http://www2.satoh-lab.nii.ac.jp/~stylix/face">http://www2.satoh-lab.nii.ac.jp/~stylix/face</a>]
    - -- Tasks -- Applying an existing client UI for our Lab's face retrieval backend.
- Technical skills: C++, OpenCV, PHP, HTML5, JavaScript, Linux HPC, iOS, Python, etc.

# 2013 - Summer Internship

- at 楽天技術研究所、Rakuten Institute of Technology [RIT], Shinagawa, Japan
- Project:
  - Instance search based image retrieval for character recognition
    - -- Tasks -- Using an instance search technique to recognize characters in a natural scene.
- **Technical skills**: C++, OpenCV, PHP, HTML5, JavaScript, CSS, etc.

# 2011 and 2012 - Internship Student

- at 国立情報学研究所、National Institute of Informatics [NII], Tokyo, Japan
- Projects:
  - Agricultural Image Processing System February to August 2011
    - -- **Tasks** -- Developing a tool to extract useful information from the existing agriculture video collections e.g. growth rate, seasons, day-night, sky-detect, weather, etc.
  - Instance Search Demonstration System January to June 2012
    - -- Tasks -- Building a web interface for sending image query and receiving the related commercial video from Japanese TV.
- Technical skills: C# .NET, C++, OpenCV, PHP, HTML5, JavaScript, ¡Query, CSS, etc.

# 2007 - Research and Development (R&D) Intern

- at IWANE Laboratory [岩根], Bangkok, Thailand
- Tasks: Developing a video street view module for a Windows Mobile 6
- Project:
  - 3D Video Player for Windows Mobile [for **360-degree** video]
  - 2D Video Player for Windows Mobile [for **300-degree** video]
- Technical skills: C# .NET, OpenGL, DirectX, OpenCV, etc.

#### **TECHNICAL EXPERIENCES**

Programming language and Script:

C++ (skillful), C, Node.JS, Python, Go, C#, Java, JavaScript, Bash, Objective-C, HTML5, PHP, CSS, jQuery, SQL, ASP, and Assembly

# Technology and Library:

Docker, MongoDB, Hyperledger, Express, Passport, Elasticsearch, OpenCV, MPI, OpenMP, SQL, HDF5, Hadoop, .NET Framework, WPF, Silverlight, DirectX, OpenGL, Tensorflow

#### Platform:

Computer: Linux (HPC, RedHat, CentOS, Ubuntu, Debian), Linux prefix (LFS), Windows Mobile: Android, Apple iOS, Windows Phone

#### Development environment:

Codelite, VS Code, PyCharm, Codeblocks, Microsoft Visual Studio, XCode, and Eclipse

#### Others:

Computer network and infrastructure design, maintenance, and support

# PROJECT EXPERIENCES (SELECTED)

#### • System and Framework

- 1. NII KAORI Person Search Interface, a wrapper web interface for searching person with video clip results (HTML5, JavaScript, PHP, 2013)
- 2. Commercial Film Retrieval, server-client based video retrieval (C++, OpenCV, HTML5, JavaScript, PHP, 2012)
- 3. Instance Search, NII student internship project (C++, HTML5, JavaScript, PHP, 2012)

# • Standalone Application

- 1. Agriculture Analyser, NII student internship project (C#, OpenCV, 2011)
- 2. Video Surveillance Summarization and Retrieval (C#, OpenCV, 2010)
- 3. Seam Carving for Content-Aware Image Resizing: senior project (C#, OpenCV, 2008)
- 4. Gesture Analyser for multi-touch gallery (C#, OpenCV, WPF, 2008)
- 5. 3D Video Player with GPS based map on Windows Mobile 6.1 (C#, DirectX, 2008)